<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Hugo website – Mortons Emotion and Imagination</title>
    <link>/post/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mortons Emotion and Imagination on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 11:57:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/post/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Emotion</title>
      <link>/2024/06/11/imagining-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:45:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/06/11/imagining-emotion/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Psychological research regarding philosophical treatments of emotion. Can look at Elaine Fox (2008) “Emotion
Science.” Discusses what scientists have learned about the emotions. Copp (2007) talks about morality in
terms of emotions, beliefs and rules.
Part 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All emotion involves imagination [1].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imagination involves representing something to ourselves [8].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of imagination, we can “see” anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our emotions inspire us to search for actions that will address particular problems which we face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But we must make sure to distinguish between emotion and mood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g., emotions have objects whereas moods do not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our emotions put pressures on our thoughts, desires, conjectures, fantasies, and perceptions. This
pressure in turn is interpreted as a feeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are different categories of emotion understood as a four way distinction between emotion and
mood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A way to understand this, is by understanding our emotions as a two-way cross-cutting distinction
between passions and sentiments and another between moods and emotions [48].
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mood and passion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mood and sentiment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emotion and passion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emotion and sentiment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failing to Imagine Emotion</title>
      <link>/2024/06/11/failing-to-imagine-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:46:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/06/11/failing-to-imagine-emotion/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a common practice that we imagine other people’s emotions. This is how we understand their
motives, actions, and feelings [54].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our practice of imagining the emotions and perspectives of other people is a central feature of human
social life [56].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perspective is our ability to imagine the point of view of another. By perspective we plan our actions
and predict the actions of others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is possible that we misimagine others however. We might imagine a loved one to be in distress even
though they are not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imagined fictional personalities are not an illusion. The characters themselves have real motives and
actions. However, they can be an invitation to isslusion by allowing us to connect possible characters,
personalities with possible motives and actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“We are rarely aware of the limits of our imaginative grasp of one another in everyday live, and of how
often we do not manage to imagine at all” [88]. Sometimes we are unable to predict the motivations and
emotions of others. This is because of an asymmetry between actions with good outcomes and others
with not so good outcomes. “The asymmetry is that admiration often blocks the desire to understand,
while frustration or disapporval often prompts it, so that we are more aware of the difficulties in
imagining uncooperative people” [91].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While we might understand why someone commits an awful act, we cannot understand how they are
able to commit the awful action. This is because we “raise the stakes for explanation of evil actions”
[94]. These sorts of actions require a more thorough explanation. Yet, these do not have a special
motive, but it seems that Morton attributes these to a weakness of will. I am not convinced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distinctions between empathy and sympathy may either be:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emotional resonance - feeling what another feels (e.g., Peter Goldie 2004 “On Personality,” or 2011
“Anti-empathy”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emotional appropriateness — having a suitable reaction to another person’s situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emotional identification — having an emotion that makes you take their purposes to your heart
and their troubles as your concern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we attempt to understand, by imagining, someone else’s experiences and motivations, we have to
“manage a tradeoff between completeness and accuracy” [109].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Moral Emotions</title>
      <link>/2024/06/11/imagining-moral-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:47:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/06/11/imagining-moral-emotions/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general point is that we want to know when to hope that someone is regretful (perhaps for a mistake) or contemptuous (perhaps towards a fake), and when to fear that they may be resentful (perhaps that one has told an inconvenient truth) or grateful (perhaps because someone has done their job more thoroughly than required). And we do not want these conclusions to just depend on what is conventionally or intuitively considered good or moral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our moral terms are motivated by our emotions. [Jesse Prinz, the emotional contruction of morals;
Jonathan Haidt, “The Emotional Dog and Its Rational Tail: A social intuitiounist approach to moral
judgment.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although the way our emotions make us feel about a situation may be inappropriate, or misguided, we
cannot retract the fact that our emotional response was thus. However, we can have other emotions
regarding our initial emotional response which are a kind of retraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are some emotions which allow us multiple perspectives. For instance, we might imagine a
subjective perspective, say you feel the pain your friend might have experienced when his girlfriend
broke up with him, but you might also have access to a more objective emotion wherein you feel the
hurt caused by your friend when he cheated on his girlfriend. “ ‘Objective’ here means, I think, not
that it is some sort of physical fact, but that a person who saw the situation objectively — that is,
not through one’s own eyes — would react that way” [128]. Moral emotions, given these multiple
perspectives then, are imagined “complex emotions built out of two others. . . ” [131]. “The first is an
attitude to a real or imagined occupant of a point of view. . . . The second is an attitude from this
point of view towards an act or pattern of action” [131].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a great diversity and variety of moral emotions. These can correspond with imagined points
of view. Further, “moral emotions, in all their discord and variety, are generated by hanging simple
emotions towards people and situations along branching points of view” [139], a point of view which
can vary. This might account for the problematic effects that empathy can sometimes manifest in our
behaviors to strangers. Yet, having two perspectives which are oppossing [subjective and objective (in
part)] to one another, will allow us to act as “impartial observers distant from the immediate situation.
And in this direction we come eventually to a completely detached but rather inscrutable point of
view valuing only humanity, justice, welfare” [139]. Morton suggests that this process is similar to that
expressed by Lawrence Kohlberg in his “stages of moral development.” However, it is not clear whether
this is something that occurs when a child matures through the stages of development from child to adult, or is it something relegated only to a kind of moral development which I think can come about
later in life also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, this varied perspective can also to not discount immediately our emotional responses to
situations. For instance, we might have an emotional experience because someone mentioned a crude
remark. We might initially think that we are over reacting, but as we continue to think about it and
attempt to imagine scenarios wherein the remark was benign, it appears to us that there was in fact no
justifcation for the remark and therefore our initial emotional response is appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moral Emotions which do not necessarily enable moral learning, or possibly prevent it: smugness,
hypocracy, etc. For instance, “[w]hen you are smug, you feel approval from some respected source,
directed at your general character and actions” [150]. This allows three things:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An attitude to others wherein you hold some advantage over them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You become satisfied in your current state and therefore do not need change of any kind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 and 2 lead to complacency wherein you become comfortable in maintaining ideas of superiority
over others; even if these ideas are not warranted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Apt Emotions</title>
      <link>/2024/06/11/motivating-apt-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:57:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/06/11/motivating-apt-emotions/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;How do we come to have apt emotional expressions? On the one hand, it might be fruitless to criticize another for the lack of an emotion they are not able to produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t just decide to be happy, or to have some chosen belief. And if you are experiencing self-punishing remorse when regret would make more sense, it is not enough to simply tell yourself so. p. 198&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how true is this? What power do we have over our emotions? Some possibilities include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change our states of mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attend selectively to evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choose who to associate with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we should not conclude that we have no power over what we feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the main idea of this book and how this final part will develop it. We can have an enormours
range of emtions, in part because our flexible imaginations allow us emotions structured around
multiple points of view. So it is a real question which emotions are best for us, and when. And
since emotions with multiple points of view are central to moral life, the question allows us to
wonder which moral attitudes are harmful, perverse, or counterproductive. One way of making
the question manageable is to consider families of moral emotions—one example consists of the
much discussed cousins regret, remorse, guilt, shame, and embarrassment — and the ways in
which we can slide into one of them when another would make more sense. [157]
If we have a concept of a particular emotion, we are then better able to experience that emotion. From
families of emotions, we can choose which ones we ought to encourage one another to feel and determine
which ones are obstacles to our moral lives [158].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different emotions resemble one another. Some emotions resemble others in the way they subjectively
feel whereas others resemble one another in regards to the way that motivate an agent to think or act.
The important resemblances are those that relate to our moral lives, for instance shame and disapproval.
Here, imagination becomes relevant because we might ask whether a particular emotion was appropriate,
e.g., disapproval and anger, in a particular situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One family of emotions includes sharme, regret, embarrassment and remorse. Embarrasment and regret
are the outliers, for instance, embarrassment is more shallow than shame or remorse. We might see
shame on one end and remorse on the other. For instance, shame occurs when we “we apprehend a trait
as an attribute of ourselves which we take to exemplify the polar opposite of a self-relevant value’.” “In
other words, the person experiencing shame feels that she is inadequate in some way that is important,
as revealed by some action” [160]. Embarrassment however, is different from shame in that it includes
a recognition of the ridicoulusness of your own actions. Further however, this recognition may either be
followed by your own amusement or your own disgust [161].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shame-like emotions are similar to someone staringt malevolently at you [164] while regret-like emotions
result, sometimes, from events over which you had no control and which you likely had no other real
options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remorse, unlike regret, can continue to feel almost indefinitely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moral emotions are emotions of appeal, e.g., some emotions like regret or remorse may feel like an
appeal from someone affected by some past action taken by us. But each moral emotion involve varying
potential perspectives of our own actions, or actions taken by others but through our own point of view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, there are some emotions which may be hard to hard to fit between the emotion and either
the target of that emotion, an attitude to a point of view inferred by that emotion etc [181—182].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two different emotions which can be expressed in pride. One set might be contrasted against
humility while the other can be contrasted with shame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As mentioned, there is a danger that pride can result in smugness which hinders moral development
rather then its consequent; self-respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absurdity can be contrasted with despair. Given the imagination and our moral emotions, we may
imagine a situation we find ourselves in from the perspective of others, and through this realize how
absurd our situation is. On the other hand, despair “recognizes the futility of hope” [165]. We might
imagine a situation we find ourselves in, however, in imagining, we recognize that our situation really is
hopeless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While we cannot decide to feel differently than we do at any given moment, this does not mean that we
do not have control over our emotions. “I will give three reasons why having the concept of a particular
moral emotion — having it in a full way by having a word for it, being able to describe cases where
people experience it, and being able to imagine having it — makes it easier to enter into the emotion”
[199].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“If we have a name for a pattern of behaviour, then we are more likely to notice it when it occurs,
and having noticed it, we are in a better position to imagine being in a state that would lead to it,
and being able to imagine it, we are nearer to being able to enter into it” [199]. This is important
because as I have shown before, Morton believes that emotions correspond with various pressures.
Further, pressures can be seen as a kind of motivation, so some emotion might be important to
have because it will pressure a moral agent to perform certain actions in certain situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“So with moral emotions we have a fixed frame of points of view, which needs just to have different
basic emotions attached to it” [200].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The third reason is the vividness and emotional resonance of our imagination of people” [200].
“. . . The concept of the emotion tells one what personalities to imagine, in which roles in the
perspective structure of the emotion” [200]. Doing this is a way of “making moral emotions
available, by giving them attention, grasping their perspective structure, and imagining occupants
of their points of view” [201].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultimately, moral imagining is a virtue we ought to cultivate [206].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
