<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Hugo website – Aesthetics of Identity</title>
    <link>/post/aesthetics-of-identity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aesthetics of Identity on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 18:23:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/post/aesthetics-of-identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrality in Fiction</title>
      <link>/2024/06/10/neutrality-in-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 18:19:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/06/10/neutrality-in-fiction/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;John Gilmore defines the continuity view about expressive emotions, as emotions that are apt &lt;em&gt;if and only if&lt;/em&gt; they correctly represent the source of that emotion, if that source has the qualities that are relevant for the expression of that emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The envy I feel in thinking that my colleague cruises around town on a vintage Vespa &lt;em&gt;motorino&lt;/em&gt; is inapt if he does no such thing.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is reason to think that the criteria which an emotion&amp;rsquo;s apt expressions are grounded in are dependent on question of whether the source is real of fictional. What grounds the criterial qualities of emotionally apt responses to fiction are the functions that prompt the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is true that works of art standardly evoke a given emotion through supplying reasons that point to its object&amp;rsquo;s possession of the relevant features. . . . However, we can see how works of art also sometimes represent people, events, states of affairs, and so on in ways designed to elicit certain emotions &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; supplying what would count as reasons for those emotions if they were felt toward analogous things in real life.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Francis Ford Coppola&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Apocalypse Now&lt;/em&gt; where the music &amp;ldquo;Ride of the Valkyries&amp;rdquo; is used to elicit first enjoyment, and then shock, horror, and dread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wagner&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Lohengrin&lt;/em&gt; is used to distract us from the fact that the &lt;em&gt;The Great Dictator&lt;/em&gt; is literally &amp;rsquo;toying with the world&#39;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, an emotion&amp;rsquo;s criterial qualities can be grounded in entertainment, pleasure, and assorbtion and do not always need to be rationalized by the facts the objects correspond to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. 91&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. 115&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
