<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mortons Emotion and Imagination on Philosophy of Games</title>
    <link>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mortons Emotion and Imagination on Philosophy of Games</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:57:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Emotion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:45:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-emotion/</guid>
      <description>Psychological research regarding philosophical treatments of emotion. Can look at Elaine Fox (2008) “Emotion Science.” Discusses what scientists have learned about the emotions. Copp (2007) talks about morality in terms of emotions, beliefs and rules. Part 1:&#xA;All emotion involves imagination [1]. Imagination involves representing something to ourselves [8]. Because of imagination, we can “see” anything. Our emotions inspire us to search for actions that will address particular problems which we face.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failing to Imagine Emotion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/failing-to-imagine-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:46:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/failing-to-imagine-emotion/</guid>
      <description>It is a common practice that we imagine other people’s emotions. This is how we understand their motives, actions, and feelings [54]. Our practice of imagining the emotions and perspectives of other people is a central feature of human social life [56]. Perspective is our ability to imagine the point of view of another. By perspective we plan our actions and predict the actions of others. It is possible that we misimagine others however.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Moral Emotions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-moral-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:47:23 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-moral-emotions/</guid>
      <description>The general point is that we want to know when to hope that someone is regretful (perhaps for a mistake) or contemptuous (perhaps towards a fake), and when to fear that they may be resentful (perhaps that one has told an inconvenient truth) or grateful (perhaps because someone has done their job more thoroughly than required). And we do not want these conclusions to just depend on what is conventionally or intuitively considered good or moral.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Apt Emotions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/motivating-apt-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:57:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:5068/docs/example/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/motivating-apt-emotions/</guid>
      <description>How do we come to have apt emotional expressions? On the one hand, it might be fruitless to criticize another for the lack of an emotion they are not able to produce.&#xA;You can&amp;rsquo;t just decide to be happy, or to have some chosen belief. And if you are experiencing self-punishing remorse when regret would make more sense, it is not enough to simply tell yourself so.&#xA;But how true is this?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
