<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Schectman, On Narrative on Philosophy of Games</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/philosophers/schectman-narrative/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Schectman, On Narrative on Philosophy of Games</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 16:50:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/philosophers/schectman-narrative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sche View From Everywhere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/philosophers/schectman-narrative/sche-view-from-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 12:52:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/philosophers/schectman-narrative/sche-view-from-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-view-from-everywhere-temporal-self-experience-and-the-good-life&#34;&gt;&#xA;  The View from everywhere: temporal self-experience and the Good life&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#the-view-from-everywhere-temporal-self-experience-and-the-good-life&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I agree with Velleman that our experience is inherently multi-perspectival but argue that there are more than two relevant perspectives and reject the claim that these perspectives have independent interests.” (&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;zotero://select/groups/2202160/items/9C7EPSI3&#34;&gt;Schechtman, 2022, p. 1&lt;/a&gt;) (&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;zotero://open-pdf/groups/2202160/items/NSHV9LH7?page=1&amp;amp;annotation=QR75SABM&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of trying to measure well-being. On the first, the well-being of a life is measured by an accumulation of all of the moments of that life. One way to understand this is by looking, for instance, at consecutive moments of a person&amp;rsquo;s life, and determining how, when the person looks back, they feel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schechtman on Personhood and Personal Identity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/philosophers/schectman-narrative/schechtman-on-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 10:45:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/philosophers/schectman-narrative/schechtman-on-personhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two questions which an early Marya Schechtman asks regarding identity and personhood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What history am I defined by (re-identification and bodily criterion)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are my values, beliefs, and desires (self-knowledge, psychological criterion)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Such questions are important when we are often attempting to &lt;em&gt;discover&lt;/em&gt; who we are, or define who we might be. This may become necessary when attempting to determine how to reconcile our past, current or future behaviors. A way to do so is by determining who we take ourselves to be and calculating what kinds of behaviors are a likely consequence. A popular example is that of someone who seems to remember leading soldiers into battle at Waterloo. But lets further imagine that they were born in 1980 rather than 1780. This is an extreme case however, but there is a more mundane case that can reflect the concern we associate with identity claims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
