<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Morton&#39;s Emotion and Imagination on Philosophy of Games</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Morton&#39;s Emotion and Imagination on Philosophy of Games</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Emotion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:45:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-emotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    Psychological research regarding philosophical treatments of emotion. Can look at Elaine Fox (2008) “Emotion&#xA;Science.” Discusses what scientists have learned about the emotions. Copp (2007) talks about morality in&#xA;terms of emotions, beliefs and rules.&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Part 1:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All emotion involves imagination [1].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Imagination involves representing something to ourselves [8].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because of imagination, we can “see” anything.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our emotions inspire us to search for actions that will address particular problems which we face.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But we must make sure to distinguish between emotion and mood.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;e.g., emotions have objects whereas moods do not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our emotions put pressures on our thoughts, desires, conjectures, fantasies, and perceptions. This&#xA;pressure in turn is interpreted as a feeling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are different categories of emotion understood as a four way distinction between emotion and&#xA;mood.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A way to understand this, is by understanding our emotions as a two-way cross-cutting distinction&#xA;between passions and sentiments and another between moods and emotions [48].&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;mood and passion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;mood and sentiment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;emotion and passion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;emotion and sentiment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failing to Imagine Emotion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/failing-to-imagine-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:46:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/failing-to-imagine-emotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is a common practice that we imagine other people’s emotions. This is how we understand their&#xA;motives, actions, and feelings [54].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our practice of imagining the emotions and perspectives of other people is a central feature of human&#xA;social life [56].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Perspective is our ability to imagine the point of view of another. By perspective we plan our actions&#xA;and predict the actions of others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is possible that we misimagine others however. We might imagine a loved one to be in distress even&#xA;though they are not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Imagined fictional personalities are not an illusion. The characters themselves have real motives and&#xA;actions. However, they can be an invitation to isslusion by allowing us to connect possible characters,&#xA;personalities with possible motives and actions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“We are rarely aware of the limits of our imaginative grasp of one another in everyday live, and of how&#xA;often we do not manage to imagine at all” [88]. Sometimes we are unable to predict the motivations and&#xA;emotions of others. This is because of an asymmetry between actions with good outcomes and others&#xA;with not so good outcomes. “The asymmetry is that admiration often blocks the desire to understand,&#xA;while frustration or disapporval often prompts it, so that we are more aware of the difficulties in&#xA;imagining uncooperative people” [91].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While we might understand why someone commits an awful act, we cannot understand how they are&#xA;able to commit the awful action. This is because we “raise the stakes for explanation of evil actions”&#xA;[94]. These sorts of actions require a more thorough explanation. Yet, these do not have a special&#xA;motive, but it seems that Morton attributes these to a weakness of will. I am not convinced.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Distinctions between empathy and sympathy may either be:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;emotional resonance - feeling what another feels (e.g., Peter Goldie 2004 “On Personality,” or 2011&#xA;“Anti-empathy”)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;emotional appropriateness — having a suitable reaction to another person’s situation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;emotional identification — having an emotion that makes you take their purposes to your heart&#xA;and their troubles as your concern.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When we attempt to understand, by imagining, someone else’s experiences and motivations, we have to&#xA;“manage a tradeoff between completeness and accuracy” [109].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Moral Emotions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-moral-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:47:23 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/imagining-moral-emotions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The general point is that we want to know when to hope that someone is regretful (perhaps for a mistake) or contemptuous (perhaps towards a fake), and when to fear that they may be resentful (perhaps that one has told an inconvenient truth) or grateful (perhaps because someone has done their job more thoroughly than required). And we do not want these conclusions to just depend on what is conventionally or intuitively considered good or moral. [Morton, 117]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Apt Emotions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/motivating-apt-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 12:57:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/books/mortons-emotion-and-imagination/motivating-apt-emotions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do we come to have apt emotional expressions? On the one hand, it might be fruitless to criticize another for the lack of an emotion they are not able to produce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t just decide to be happy, or to have some chosen belief. And if you are experiencing self-punishing remorse when regret would make more sense, it is not enough to simply tell yourself so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But how true is this? What power do we have over our emotions? Some possibilities include the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
